Welcome to the 11th episode of under the
hood. So today this episode is going to
be we are going to talk about AI or AI
related feature. Um and today with me I
have Monica. Hi Monica.
>> Hi Vincent. Thank you. Thank you. So
tell tell us a little bit about yourself
and uh how do you work with uh with AI
and what you know what type of feature
are you are you working with in your
team. Uh yes so I'm a senior software
engineer working in connected
experiences team which is part of AI
experiences workload here and I have
been in Microsoft since 2016 and I have
been focusing on various areas but
mostly on connected experiences for
integrating business central with
Microsoft 365 like teams outlook or with
power platform
>> and uh my introduction to co-pilot space
is very recent
uh where we got an interest and need for
integrating AI into business central uh
in a natural experience so that users
can become more productive easily
without even thinking of how to write
prompts and how to talk to copilot and
that's where we started thinking of
these experiences and that's how I was
introduced to copilot
>> so it's fair to say a lot of the work
and the features you are working on are
very close to the user and the user
experience right
>> definitely definitely a lot of the
features are about uh in the client
experience in business central.
>> Yes.
>> Mhm. So let's talk a little bit about um
the summarizing with copilot because
that's one of the feature you worked on
recently. Um so can you briefly describe
for for those who haven't seen it can
you briefly describe what what this
feature does and what it is. Yeah.
>> Oh definitely. So summarizing with
copilot highlights what's most important
and urgent for the user on almost every
business central page. So it's just one
click uh which can produce very
rotailored and concise text for the user
to help user make decisions faster uh
using copalot.
>> Mhm. Okay. So so and how where is where
is summary shown in the in the page?
>> Yes. Exactly. So uh initially we started
with uh focusing on certain pages like
uh heavy data pages like customers and
sales orders or items which requires uh
uh very fast decision making abilities
as well. Uh but then eventually we
created a platformwide capability. So
summarization with copilot is available
on any business central uh single entity
pages like card documents or list plus.
So customer pages,
>> customer sales orders, any uh single
entity pages. Uh and not only that, it's
also available with custom pages. Uh so
if uh partners have created some
customer card pages or customer document
pages that will be there that will work
without any
>> where is it shown on the page?
>> Uh so it it is shown on a new area what
we call a summary fact box. So it will
be shown in the fact boxes pane and
>> on the side and the side right on the
top. So
>> okay,
>> it's uh very visible on the page. Yes.
So let's go under the hood. Tell us a
little bit about uh you know that's the
title of this of this podcast. So let's
uh let's tell us a little bit about how
that was uh built. You know what how how
do we produce that that summary?
>> Yes. Um so uh I think summarization was
built in a way that it does more than
just summarizing what you see on the UI.
uh so we wanted to build uh something
that can also produce insights uh out of
the data that is available for for an
entity. So uh what what do you mean by
insights? Let's start with that. Right?
So it's pretty pretty much data points
that are currently useful given what is
the user's role or the task. So the way
we build summarization, it's pretty much
a three-step process. uh we collect data
for which for the entity you're trying
to summarize with.
>> But it's not only what's on the page.
>> Exactly. It's not only what's on the
page. It's it's the related entities. So
it's the statistics pages that are
related to the current uh current
entity. It's the facts from the fact
boxes uh and so on. Uh so wherever we
could find aggregated data, we collect
all that data uh and put it in a
structured format and then send it to
LLM to find insights out of that data.
And as I said insights are basically
data points that are important for the
user uh at that point of moment right uh
and uh we also ask uh AI to make scoring
for these insights. So based on the
certain guiding questions or based on
the data context that we have given uh
and not only that we also make copilot
think about the users context. So what's
the user's role and given all this
context AI comes up with the decision
engine where it comes up with a list of
insights that are most important and
then we summarize those uh and that's
just not summarizing
>> so you have a prompt that uh where you
actually so you gather all this data
>> yes
>> and you have a prompt just so I
understand you know so you have a prompt
that uh where you actually asking uh the
the LLM what's you know try to rank this
insight which one are the most relevant
for that particular user to give some
context
>> exactly about the first where you are.
That's the first prompt. Yes. Uh we call
it find insights prompt followed by and
then it produces a list of uh insights
and scores them
>> uh based on relevance and importance and
urgency um and other different huristics
and then
>> we take the output of that prompt and
send it in the second prompt what we
call as summarize prompt which pretty
much uh takes looks into score and only
selects the top uh bullet points that we
want to show uh and uh then does the
markdown for it in the way that we also
make sure that prompt uh always refers
back to the original data for grounding
so user knows where the data is coming
from.
>> So how many prompts do you have on for
generating the it's basically a pipeline
of prompts right?
>> It is a pipeline of I just did a major
category of two but like the first
prompt in itself uh we do run it in
parallel for each data source. So we
categorize uh data sources into three
for now the fields from the current page
the related pages and fact boxes and
these run in parallel uh because we also
want it to be performant uh so in a way
that you can say it's a pipeline of
different prompts. Yes.
>> Okay. Yeah. So it's it's interesting
because many people you know are
familiar with your chat experience your
copilot chat the chat GPT and you can
easily uh you know think of an AI
feature as you you ask a question and
you get an answer which is basically one
prompt and one reply but but as you
described with that example there's a
lot of features in our product where you
have to use multiple prompt
>> for almost every platform capability
feature that we have chat autofill
summarize uh analysis assist. Uh all of
these are definitely multi-prompt you
like I don't know I think uh for example
the autofill feature has five or six
prompts.
>> Definitely. Yes.
>> Interesting. So um uh how does copilot
know which related entities or statistic
it should be using? You know is that is
that is that a copilot thing or is that
is that just normal code or you know how
do we gather that data?
>> It's a mixture of both. we definitely
leverage existing business uh business
central structures and metadata. So uh
for example when we select the data we
come up with the statistics uh we come
up with the pages as related pages
definitions in the way that actions on
the current page that lead to other
pages are in a way related pages
>> but then we don't send the data from all
of those pages cuz it could be lot of
data. So we filter out only the pages
that are named statistics because that's
where the aggregated data exist and
that's very good for summarization that
we realized over multiple uh efforts and
prompt engineering and all that and
that's how we come up with this if an
action points to a page and if the page
is uh has statistics in it then we take
that data into account and send it to
LM. Okay. So we made that decision at
some stage we kind of say okay the these
this is where there's an assumption that
that statistics pages contain relevant
data for summization.
>> So that's one of the
>> potentially we could have chosen some
other data. Yes. There's some decision
to make in what you
>> Exactly. And we came up with this
decision over multiple uh over multiple
attempts. Right. So we started with
sending pretty much uh all the ledger
entries and all and we soon realized uh
it's not very performant cuz it has to
process a lot of data. So we want to
send already some aggregated data. So
that's one uh way. Uh we are also
sending for example some related data
from the fact boxes which is another uh
way of aggregated data in business
central already. So we're definitely
leveraging business central metadata
structure that existed already. Uh so
that was that was one approach and then
beyond that we asked copilot to also
figure out what is related for depending
on the user's role. So copilot also does
some more filtering after the after we
send the data. So it's a mix of both
code in the sense that we before sending
it to LLM we figure out from the code
point of view what could be sent and
then copilot on top of it decides what
could be filtered even more. So we're
trying to be a little bit smart about it
and kind of pick some data and kind of
use copilot to refine it. I remember you
know we I remember very early in the
very early days of this feature when we
started talking about doing a
summarization you did an experiment uh I
think the very I think maybe probably
the very first experiment on sum on
summarization where you tell us a little
bit about it. I think there was
something about you send all the data on
the page and uh
>> yeah so we started with as uh simple as
just sending um just sending the fields
that you see on the page and then
summarizing it. It was pretty much a
simple prompt uh saying to this is the
data summarize it. But then over the
over the time we realized the true value
lies in uh preventing users from
clicking multiple tabs uh and then
getting faster data so that they can
make faster decision- making and that
was the purpose. So soon then we started
with uh sending more and more data u
right and uh and then one approach we
took is all the fields that could have
been related by table relationships that
could have been one approach of defining
related data right um and we tried with
that experiment u and soon like there we
we came up with a bunch of uh uh
entities that could be related to for
example sales order and we came up
pretty much with entire database in a
like how deep do you want to go in terms
of table relations and so on. So we did
a lot of experiments there and that's
how we came up with multiple iterations
and came up with the approach that we
have taken now which is to use wherever
we have the aggregated data in business
central
>> yeah but that's interesting because just
summarizing what's on the page is not
really relevant because you can just
look at the page exactly the idea as you
mentioned as I understand is you you we
we look at related things and without
having so that that can prevent the
users from or help the users and and uh
doesn't have to you look because usually
that's what you do when you when you
want to get some insights from say a
customer or sales order you go and click
around and try to gather the data so we
kind of say that copilot does that for
you in
>> exactly that that is the idea right so
the way I see summarization Vincent is
basically there are two main uh tracks
that we can keep working on for
improving summarization overall and
that's how we started with there's the
data context which is what kind of data
to send is what we are talking about but
there's another parallel context which
is data about the user. So uh what we
intend to do is right now we are sending
role but eventually we intend to also
make sure that we understand what was
the intent of the user to open this
particular page
>> and the more context we have about the
user the more context we have about the
entity for which we are summarizing the
better the summaries would be. So how do
you that's interesting because uh so
that's what's basically maybe what
what's coming with this feature right uh
so how do you um how do you so we're
trying to guess or or determine what the
user intent is so how do we do that is
that where for example where you
navigate from or you know what what what
are
>> exactly so there are multiple ways to uh
determine the user intent uh the
definitely role is one of them so we
already know for example a business
manager is usually interested in
business KPIs or a warehouse manager
would be interested in inventory details
or sales order would be interested in
how is customer uh doing with the sales
uh so on right so role definitely helps
but there is other ways to define what
could be the intent of the user on this
page for example the most uh frequently
used pages or what was the navigation
pattern that user followed u to reach to
this entity uh so that could kind of
indicate what was the intent of the user
so we definitely want to explore those
parts as That sounds sounds exciting. So
that's the next generation of summary,
right?
>> Yes. Yes, definitely. Of we also want to
stabilize uh more and more with the
current version and and then in future
we do have plans of increasing both the
tracks the user context track but also
the data context. So we'll have more
sources of data. Right now all the
sources that I mentioned are coming from
the business central database itself but
we could easily think of uh you know
integrating with external data be it um
data from LinkedIn or any other external
>> sources put potentially point on your
one drive or something and have another
thing we could that be really cool.
>> So how's the can you see you know
telemetry we monitor the usage of that
feature right? Yeah.
>> What can you see there? Is that a good
usage?
>> So, there's definitely very good early
adoption. We are seeing that. Um uh
there's a little bit of lesser
percentage of people clicking show more.
>> Uh which could indicate uh that uh
already the the the data points that
they are seeing might be enough for them
to help make their task uh perform
better.
>> Can you tell us a little bit what what's
the show more is?
>> Yes. So uh as we mentioned that you see
the summary in the summary fact box
right and right there you only see like
two or three bullet points of summary
text which is the highest score insights
that copilot came up with uh put into
natural language. Uh and then you get to
see like most three important things
that you need to know about this entity.
But if you're curious and if you want to
know more about them then you can click
a show more button in the fact box and
then it will open the chat experience
which will give you more insights. So
more number of bullet points and of
course the reason that it shows up in
the chat experience is then you can talk
with the co-pilot or and know more about
the data points or follow up ask
questions exactly
>> in natural language. Natural language
which is pretty cool too. So um so you
this is this is all AI development right
and so as you mentioned it's kind of
it's kind of new still for for for many
of us right so what so how was it to
develop this this AI feature was it did
you do a lot of prompt engineering for
example
>> definitely yes prompt engineering
definitely um I think this was also one
of my big AI features and what I learned
uh in in the sense from with building AI
I features is that there's definitely a
lot of prompt engineering but there's a
lot of architecture surrounded around
the prompts. uh for example making sure
that the data context is structured uh
making sure that the output is uh kind
of a little bit more deterministic but
since the the nature of AI is
non-deterministic in itself what I
learned more is that tests are super
super important especially because you
change one line of prompt and the
response could be completely different
and you would want to do it in multiple
iterations over your development ment
cycle of the feature. So tests are
definitely way more
>> Yeah. So let's talk a little bit about
test because um especially for a feature
like summary uh you know so everybody
knows everybody understand the concept
of test you know you have an input and
you have an expected output uh and you
know in the old days it was pretty
simple like you enter a number and you
expect another number there or something
like that right uh when we're talking
about summary and you know AI we do a
lot of things with natural language like
summary is a good example of a of of an
AI feature leveraging natural language
Um it's no there's no it's a little
harder to determine what's right or
wrong because you get a you get some
text in natural language right and and
it can be phrased in many ways but so
how do you how do you test that or you
know that this is actually a good
summary or bad summary or an accurate
summary so tell us a little bit about
how you test
>> this is very interesting question and it
was also one of the very uh big
challenges for us uh to determine what
is a good summary or what is not a good
summary
Um so when it comes to testing AI
features there are different uh tests
that you have to keep in mind. There's
definitely the harm test uh making sure
that the response never contains any
harmful content uh and that has kind
that is kind of a bit more uh in your
control. You have a set list of uh harms
and now it's even available in Azure AI
foundry. So you could uh test your
content against those harms and uh make
sure
>> and typically you we actually use an LLM
to do that.
>> Yes. All the tests that you
>> basically the you you you put your thing
through the LM you get an answer. Yes.
Exactly.
>> And then you you you take that answer
and you have another prompt.
>> Yes. that for example if you want to
test for harms yes that is that is
crafted for that particular purpose of
testing hardware you basically ask
something like I'm oversimplifying but
it's something like is there anything
with violence in that content
>> yes and that is pretty
>> will tell you yes or no
>> yes that is pretty much it right we have
something called what we call evaluate
statement prompt and this could be a
statement for example right where we say
hey this is the data can you evaluate
whether this statement is true or not
does it have a harm.
>> Uh definitely one of the new things
about uh testing with AI features is
that you use AI to test AI features.
>> Uh so that's that's good that you
brought it up. Uh so there's the harm
test, right? Uh where you have a set of
defined harms and you want to test
against those.
>> Uh then there is the accuracy test uh
which is making sure that AI is not
hallucinating. It's not it's grounded uh
>> in the data that you provided as the
input. uh and uh
>> so what's the principle of it?
>> Uh so pretty much the principle is um we
we check so grounding can be applied in
multiple ways.
>> It could be applied uh uh definitely
already at the code level. It could be
applied already at the data input level.
You could filter out the data that you
believe is probably for example for
summarization we filtered out default
values or something like that. Uh so
there's some grounding right there in
the prompt. uh engineering you can do
some grounding explicitly saying to make
sure that the data is always um that the
output is always grounded in the data.
We always uh we also use the function
calling in the sense that the insight's
output structure is um is deterministic.
So we we always tell that for each
insight please refer back to one of the
source ID from the data that we sent. So
that could be another approach for
grounding. But testing is also another
way for making sure grounding uh is
there. Uh and uh that could be done
basically asking LLM again
>> uh given this is the output summary
given this is the data can you please
confirm that the output is always from
the data.
>> Mhm. And contain the data that comes
from the output. So you just basically
ask the make sure
>> exactly. So in this case the evaluate
statement is can you please make sure
that the output is coming from the
table. That's a very common technique by
the way that used in many uh many AI
features uh where you actually
>> exactly
>> kind of check that the result is
consistent with what what you expect and
>> yes uh and for summarization to answer
your question about how do you measure a
good summary but we also have something
what we call functional test um and uh
this is like any software development
feature you would do some functional
test but here we also involve LLM so uh
and this is a bit tricky right so here
we say uh Given a role for example
warehouse manager
>> Mhm.
>> and given an item data for example that
has zero inventory
>> uh we would expect that this should be
one of the uh insights that should be
written in the final summary and this is
the functional test that we did. So we
came up with some tremendous large test
data set containing multiple roles and
multiple scenarios with different
entities. uh some for example customer
has late payments or there is a delay in
uh shipping lines or the item inventory
zero. So these are the matters that we
would expect uh to be shown in summary
because they are important uh given on
the role uh for the user or they might
be urgent given on the deadline and so
on. Uh and then
>> for example we have you have data we
have data test data where we have
customers where late payment
>> for example
>> and then we expect that to show up in
the summary. Yes. So we have another
prompt that says hey uh look at this
summary does it say something about let
>> exactly exactly and that's that's the
way we decided and then we have multiple
other metrics right uh so one of them is
certain insight is there or not but we
have we have defined a plenty of other
metrics to decide how good a summary can
be for example it needs to be certain in
certain in brief words it cannot be too
long or cannot be too short uh things
like that it it needs to be precise in
the sense if you try to with the same
data if you try to regenerate five
times, seven times
>> the form and the style of the summary
itself.
>> Form, style, precision, brevity, there
are other metrics that we define and yes
and then that's how we come up with uh a
certain way of scoring whether a summary
is good or not
>> and we want to do this as a repetitive
process. So we want to also get feedback
uh from different customers and then you
know iterate over this whole process of
measuring summary and get to a you know
our our vision of how good a summary is.
Is that the thumbs up or thumbs down or
>> that's one way definitely uh thumbs up
and thumbs down uh definitely is one way
but in general the feedback right from
partners and uh and understanding from
telemetry the patterns so we want
>> please if you're using that feature give
us a sum up or thumbs down please do
because that's useful for us and we can
definitely that can help Monica improve
the summary
>> definitely yes
>> yeah so there's another thing actually
we might do another under the hood
episode about it but we're working um uh
on doing what we call experimentation. I
don't want to tell much about it because
that's that could be a subject an entire
an entire episode but it's about
basically uh trying some things out uh
and having some metrics to verify you
know whether it's a good you know which
you know could be something for
something like try with a different
prompt and see if it gives better
results that and summary could be a
candidate for doing experiments like
this. So we would uh send you know try a
prompt on a small population of our
users and see if they give up some
something up and see if it's better but
we'll we'll get back to that.
>> Definitely. Definitely. Yes. So what
what what was your what would you say
was the um
uh you know the most challenging thing
you you mentioned tests um but did you
have any aha experience working with AI
and doing prompt especially doing prompt
engineering you know was something that
you got surprised about that you didn't
think okay wow that's that's that's how
that's how it works or you know I
wouldn't think
>> I think test definitely was one of them
how important it is especially like the
number of reiterations it takes with
prompt engineering and then there is
also the effort for model migrations. So
you need to keep up to date with the new
models. So you want to change uh which
means you need to have good test to make
sure that your feature is behaving uh as
you would want to behave even with the
newer models and so on. You want to
experiment with different kind of
models. So that's also the test is
definitely um
>> so which models are we using for that
feature?
>> Yeah. So for summarization uh we were
certain prompts were before on uh 40 um
especially the ground uh ground checks
and all and most of them were four uh 40
mini.
>> Okay.
>> And now uh we have migrated all of them
to 41 mini.
>> Okay. So why why uh mini why why so for
if you don't know the the models called
mini are actually small language model.
Uh so why
>> smaller than smaller? They're still
quite big. There are there could be even
smaller uh SM. So yeah, so these these
are smaller. Yeah, you you're right.
Correct me about it because they still
you still can't really run them on
regular hardware. So this they're still
relatively large.
>> But um so why why using these small
language models and why not using the
big models?
>> Uh it depends on the need of the
feature, right? Definitely. uh for for
summarization specifically um we believe
that 41 mini is enough uh it's also uh
performant or better performant uh so we
want the summary to be right there in
couple of seconds so it's faster so
>> what you ask yeah so basically large
model they do have more work in a sense
so if you send them same pro it will
take longer time for them to answer
right
>> yeah and exactly and there's also a a
whole idea about trying it out with
different models cuz some of the even
for summarization As I said, there's
multiple prompts involved. Some of the
prompts, for example, the scoring part
could be probably better done with uh
other models than 41 mini uh because
they might have better reasoning
capabilities and we are still figuring
out right uh to maybe try out these
newer models like 01 and so on. So
there's no right answer in a way uh but
you just select models depending on the
need of the feature.
>> Mhm. So what what how can you advise our
partners who are you know trying to
develop AI features and you know how how
should they pick their model why should
they you know uh experiment like you do
or you know what's you know what's the
what's the
>> definitely read about them understand
the differences between each of them and
then uh start with the one that meets
the closest with your need of the
feature and then yes still even if the
you believe this is the right model do
try it with other models do and that's
why have a good set of test so you could
easily switch between models and try
your features. So that's that's the way
we would do it and that's the way we
would recommend partners to do it as
well.
>> Another advantage of small language or
small language mod is that they're also
cheaper, right?
>> Definitely. Yes. But you need to
maintain them yourself. So there's also
a little bit of uh using the existing
models versus having your own models. So
>> yeah,
>> there there's trade-offs definitely.
>> All right. Okay. Any uh anything you
want to you want to say to our partners
who want to or developers who want who
want to leverage the summary? What can
they do? Is that something is that
extensible for example or you mentioned
earlier that even a custom page would
have a summary?
>> Exactly.
>> So what what can they do to make sure
that this this this feature is actually
shines for for their solution as well?
>> Definitely. Uh so the as I said
summarization works ex out of the box
with custom entities. Right now it is
not directly extensible from AL in the
sense that uh they they cannot provide
for example more data sources or they
cannot override the text that they see
in the summary in one way or another yet
but we are working on it. Uh it is one
of the top feedback that we also got
from partners that they want to have
control over uh some control over
summary in general. Uh having said that
uh this developers uh still have some
ways of uh making sure that
summarization is performing better and
that's through the metadata. They can
define their custom entities or they can
uh override the existing entities with
better metadata. If they want to include
more data sources, they could add more
fact boxes to the existing entity or
have actions that points to even more
statistics pages. So that's one way.
tool tips, captions and uh any other
descriptions and about text is one thing
that we have been always asking AL
developers to uh make sure that they are
better and descriptive and uh so because
these are the things that help co-pilot
understand the context about the entity.
So the more we will improve these
together the more AI better AI
experiences. So yeah, so if it's just as
as a minimum put good tool tips on the
on the pages, then you'll get probably a
better summary because that helps the
LLM understand what you know what
>> exactly. So that's that.
>> Um so that's for partners and
developers. For customers, I see think
of AI as your co-pilot. There's a reason
we call it co-pilot because it is uh one
of them, right? So let AI do the heavy
work uh the tedious repetitive work
>> uh while you make the actual decision
making um kind of work. So that's how I
see AI. Yes.
>> All right. Thanks Monica. That was a
little bit of insights on how we built
you know one of the many AI features in
Business Central and I think was really
you know it was great to hear about it
because it seems it seems relatively
simple uh you know just it's just a
summary of the page but there's actually
you know a lot more to it. So thank you
for sharing the nice and thank you for
watching.
>> Thank you.